shoeme.ca 2016-11-04

# Privacy Policy - SHOEme.ca

Last Updated March 16, 2015

This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use and share personal information collected on www.shoeme.ca (our “Site”), your choices regarding your information and how you can update your information. By visiting our Site from a computer or mobile device, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

#### Collection and Use of Personal Information

We (and our service providers, as described below) may collect and use your personal information for the following purposes:

  1. To fulfill your order, to communicate with you about your order and to provide customer service.
  2. To help provide a smooth, efficient shopping experience that is tailored to you.
  3. To alert you to products, services, and promotional offers and make them more relevant to you.
  4. To assist in our marketing efforts.
  5. To improve the content, design and vendor selection of our Site.
  6. To monitor and manage usage and performance of the Site and our systems.

#### Information Collection

_Information Collected Directly From You_

You can visit and browse our Site without entering any personal information. However, if you make a purchase, we will ask for the personal information necessary to fulfill your order, to communicate with you about your order and to provide customer service. Moreover, if want to have a great shopping experience and access all of our features, promotional offers and special programs, we will ask for certain personal information. For example, we will collect personal information if you subscribe to our email programs, create or share wish lists, write product reviews, enter a contest or sweepstakes, complete a survey, join our referral or loyalty programs or "Like" us on Facebook.

The information collected depends on the purpose. For example, for a purchase made with a credit card, we collect your name, phone number, email address, shipping and billing addresses, zip code and credit card information. To enhance your shopping experience, improve our marketing effectiveness or analyze Site use, we collect your purchase history, preference information (such as specific styles or brands that you prefer) and other demographic information (such as gender, age or income range) that you provide to us.

User-generated content on our Site, such as product reviews, product ratings and wish lists, may include personal information. Any such personal information is collected and may be posted on our Site.

_Information Collected Automatically_

Like most websites, we automatically collect information about your visit to our Site, including the pages and materials you view, the links you click, the searches you make, purchase information, and other actions you take on our Site. We also collect standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, your geographic location, your browser type and capabilities, your operating system, the date and time you access our Site, session information (such as page response times) and the website from which you linked to or from our Site.

_Aggregate Information_

From time to time, we may collect non-personal, statistical information about the use of our Site, such as how many visitors visit a specific page, how long they stay, and which links they click on. We use this information to help us determine which areas of our Site are most popular so we can enhance your visit. We may also group and de-personalize information into aggregate visitor data in order to describe Site usage.

The information we collect gives us an overview of our user base and our users' collective viewing, search and shopping habits and allows us, our vendors and our business partners to tailor content and discounts based on user traffic and otherwise support and enhance your shopping experience, and improve the relevance and effectiveness of our marketing efforts.

Information collected on our Site may be combined with other personal or aggregate information, including information we collect by other means (for example, if you call or email us). The combined information will also be subject to this Privacy Policy.

Cookies and Web Beacons

We use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies on our Site, in our emails and in our advertisements. Cookies, which are small data files that your Internet browser stores on your hard disk or in your browser's memory, allow us to remember you. Cookies enable you to select, place and purchase products in our shopping cart. Cookies also make it easier for you to navigate our Site (such as by storing an encrypted link to your account information, so you don't have to enter that information more than once) and enhance your shopping experience (such by storing preferences and other information you provide). Web beacons—sometimes called single-pixel gifs or action tags—are electronic images that assist in delivering cookies and provide additional information (such as which ad you clicked on to arrive at the Site). We use these technologies to monitor and analyze Site use, measure advertising effectiveness, understand shopping patterns, avoid ad duplication (by letting us know whether you have seen a particular ad before) and store certain technical information useful for interactions with our Site.

We don't store any personal information in a cookie and, when you leave our Site, we terminate our interaction with the cookie. The cookie stays on your computer or mobile device, but you can delete it (and the data that web beacons add to the cookie) by following the directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file. If you do so, you will need to log in again on your next visit to our Site and re-enter any preferences you have set. Most Internet browsers are initially set to automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser settings to decline cookies or to notify you when a cookie is being delivered. However, if you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to access or use some portions and features of our Site and may not get the best shopping experience possible.

You may occasionally get cookies from our business partners (e.g., advertisers, tracking utilities, and partner programs on our Site, such as the Google Trusted Stores program) or other third parties with links on our Site. While this is a standard practice in the online retail industry, we have no control or access to these cookies and our Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies, web beacons or other technologies by third parties. When You Subscribe To Email You can choose to receive promotional emails from us. Like most e-commerce sites, we include software code in our emails to monitor whether and when you opened the email, whether you have clicked on the images and/or links in the email, and whether your computer or mobile device is capable of receiving HTML-based email. You may also choose to receive coupons and text messages on your mobile device. You may opt out from email and mobile programs as described below under "Opting Out."

#### Disclosure and External Use of Your Personal Information

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, your personal information will not be shared with or used by third parties without your consent except where otherwise permitted or required by law). The method of consent will be appropriate for the type of personal information involved and the purposes for which it is collected, used or disclosed. Depending on the circumstances, consent may be express (i.e., you specifically agree either verbally, in writing or electronically) or implied.

  1. Service providers. We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, such as shipping and fulfilling orders, processing payments, hosting our website and product review pages, sending out information or promotional offers, tailoring site and email content, serving or managing ads, providing customer service, and analyzing Site data. Some of these companies collect and store information for us as part of their services, or we may provide them with the elements of your personal information that they need to deliver their services. These companies are prohibited from using that personal information for any other purpose.
  2. Aggregate Data. We may share aggregated, non-personal data with service providers, advertisers or other existing or potential business partners to enable our users to receive targeted information (such as product recommendations) and promotional offers and to optimize third-party offers of products and services.
  3. Affiliates. We may share personal and aggregate information collected on the Site with our affiliated family of companies. Information collected on our Site may be combined with information collected on the websites of our affiliated companies. When your personal information is shared within our family of companies, it will still be used and protected according to this Privacy Policy.
  4. Compliance with Law and Policies; Protection of Rights. We may disclose your personal information and aggregated user information as necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders and requests from law enforcement officials or government investigations; to otherwise comply with our legal obligations; to protect our legal rights and those of others; to enforce our Terms of Use or other policies or agreements; to resolve disputes; and to protect ourselves or others (for example, to reduce the risk of fraud or the use of our Site for illegal reasons).
  5. Partner Programs. From time to time, we may partner with companies that, in conjunction with trusted store or similar programs, subscription services, rewards programs or other membership programs, require that we disclose purchasing or other personal information about their members who visit our Site (for example, to obtain purchase protection or to earn points or discounts for purchases made on our Site through links from the partner site). We will disclose your personal information to the partner companies when you consent to that disclosure, including consent implied by your agreement to the applicable membership or participation rules, as necessary to support your membership in these programs.
  6. Contest/Sweepstakes Winners. We may publicly disclose the name, city and state of winners.
  7. Acquisitions or Divestitures. We may decide to sell, buy or merge our own or other businesses. Such a transaction may involve disclosing personal and other information to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. It is our practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions. In the event that we or all of our assets are acquired in such a transaction, customer information would be one of the transferred assets.
  8. Marketplace Vendors. We may share shipping information collected on the Site with our Marketplace Vendors for the purpose of delivering a product purchased from the Vendor. When your shipping information is shared with a Marketplace Vendor, it will still be used and protected according to this Privacy Policy.

#### Opting Out; Accessing and Editing Your Personal Information

You may unsubscribe at any time from our email programs by clicking on the unsubscribe link included at the bottom of every email message or by sending a request to Privacy@Shoeme.ca. We reserve the right to send you service announcements or similar administrative messages (for example, if we need to temporarily suspend our Site for maintenance), without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them. In addition, because we must communicate with you about orders that you have placed, you cannot opt out of receiving emails relating to your orders.

You may opt out at any time from receiving direct mail and other promotional correspondence by sending a request to Privacy@Shoeme.ca. You may access and edit your personal information, including your email address and whether you want to receive promotional emails, in the "Your Account" page of our Site.

You may opt out of a specific mobile messaging campaign by texting “stop”. Text "stop all" to opt out of all mobile messaging.

If you wish to cancel your account, please contact us at Privacy@Shoeme.ca. If you choose to store your credit card information in your account, it will be deleted if you cancel your account. All other information that we have collected before the cancellation may continue to be stored and used in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

You may also make requests regarding your personal information, such as requests to access information or requests to update or correct inaccurate information, by writing to Dominic Uy / CTO at Suite 400, 1500 West Pender Street, Vancouver, BC V6E 4G1 or by emailing us at Privacy@Shoeme.ca.

#### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We maintain industry-standard physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards, such as firewalls and encryption technology, to protect your information. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, and no method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. As a result, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Site, you can contact us at Privacy@Shoeme.ca.

The transmission of sensitive information (such as your credit card information) we collect from you is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL). If you choose to use a third-party payment option (such as PayPal) to pay for your order, that third party's privacy policy and security practices will also apply to the personal information collected in connection with that purchase and payment.

If you create an account on our Site, you may be asked to choose a password to protect your account and account information. We recommend that you do not disclose your password to any other person. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and account, and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your password or account.

#### Links To Other Sites

Our Site contains links to other third-party websites, and third-party websites may link to our Site. If you visited our Site through a link or a banner advertisement on another site, then that site may be collecting information from users who click on the banner or link. You should review the privacy policies on those sites to see what information is collected and how it is used. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any other website or for any information you submit to, or that is collected by, a third-party website.

#### Children's Privacy

We do not seek or knowingly collect any personal information about children under 13 years of age. If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through our Site.

#### Governing Law; Visitors Residing Outside The United States

This Privacy Policy and the privacy practices of the Site will be subject exclusively to the laws of the province of British Columbia within Canada, without regard to its conflict of law principles .If you reside outside of the Canada, by using our Site, you are responsible for compliance with local laws. You consent to the collection, transfer, storage, and use of your personal information in the Canada in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to update our Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will revise the "Last Modified" date at the top of this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to check this page for any updates before you use the Site. Your continued use of our Site following the posting of an update to this Privacy Policy will mean that you accept the terms of the updated Privacy Policy.

#### How to Contact Us with Privacy Questions

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, you can email us at Privacy@Shoeme.ca, call us at

1.866.440.7948 or write us at  
Attn: Dominic Uy  
Suite 400, 1500 West Georgia Street  
Vancouver, BC, V6G 2Z6
